Finding Aid for Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan records, 1893-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan records 1893-2014
Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan.
24 oversize volumes
45.5 linear feet
851151 Be.1/2
Michigan Society of the Daughter of the American Revolution; minutes of the state executive board, proceedings of the Michigan state conferences, publications, reports, and scrapbooks; also papers concerning their genealogical work, record of activities during World War I and II; historical files for individual chapters of the Michigan D.A.R.; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the organization (donor no. 1171 ) beginning in 1946. Periodic additions have been received.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Daughters of the American Revolution was founded in 1890 as a volunteer women's service organization dedicated to "promoting patriotism, preserving American history, and securing America's future through better education for children." The Michigan State Society of the DAR was founded in 1900. Individual local chapters of the DAR had been formed as early as 1893. In 2009, the Michigan Society had a membership of approximately 3000 women members in fifty-four local chapters. As a patriotic organization, the DAR has sought to promote and preserve family and local histories, to promote the celebration of national holidays, "to support our national defense, and to form friendships with others who share our love of God, Home, and Country."
The records of the Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan document its organization, history, and activities. As the state society of the DAR, the organization also collected material on the activities of the various local chapters. The records have been arranged into the following series: State Executive Board Minutes; State Conference Proceedings (original and published); Reports; Various Records of DAR State Historian; Miscellaneous; Chapter Records (original materials, collected material, and membership yearbooks); Publications; Scrapbooks; Topical files; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan.; Patriotic societies--Michigan.; Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Blind persons.; Cemeteries--Michigan.; Children.; Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan.; Fort Wayne (Detroit, Mich.); Grand Rapids (Mich.); Menominee (Mich.); Monroe (Mich.); Monuments and memorials.; Parades and processions.; Petoskey (Mich.); Starr Commonwealth for Boys.; Tombs and sepulchral monuments.; Women--Organizations.; World War, 1914-1918.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- State Executive Board Minutes
  - 1913-1922 (Box 1)
  - 1922-1925 (Box 1)
  - 1925-1928 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1931 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - 1937-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1943 (Box 2)
  - 1943-1946 (Box 2)
  - 1946-1949 (Box 2)
  - 1949-1952 (Box 2)
  - 1952-1955 (Box 2)
    (now labeled Minutes and Reports)
  - 1955-1958 (Box 2)
  - 1958-1961 (Box 2)
  - 1961-1964 (Box 3)
  - 1964-1967 (Box 3)
  - 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - 1973-1976 (Box 3)
  - 1976-1979 (Box 3)
  - 1979-1982 (Box 4)
  - [1983-1987 not received] (Box 4)
  - 1988-1991 (Box 4)
  - 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - [1995-1996 not received] (Box 4)
  - 1997-2000 (Box 4)
  - 2000-2009, 4 volumes (Box 5)
- State Conference Proceedings
  - 1915-1918 (Box 6)
  - 1900-1914 (Box 6)
  - 1919 (Box 6)
  - 1920 (Box 6)
  - 1921 (Box 6)
  - 1922-1924 (Box 6)
  - 1925-1927 (Box 7)
  - 1928-1930 (Box 7)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 7)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 7)
  - 1935 (Box 7)
  - 1936 (Box 7)
  - 1937 (Box 8)
  - 1938 (Box 8)
  - 1939 (Box 8)
  - 1940 (Box 8)
  - 1941 (Box 8)
  - 1942 (Box 8)
  - 1943 (Box 9)
  - 1944 (Box 9)
  - 1945 (Box 9)
    (annual report only)
  - 1946 (Box 9)
  - 1947 (Box 9)
  - 1948 (Box 9)
  - 1949 (Box 9)
- State Conference Proceedings (published)
  - 1931-1934 (Box 10)
  - 1935-1937 (Box 10)
  - 1938-1940 (Box 10)
  - 1941-1943 (Box 10)
  - 1944 (Box 10)
  - 1945 (Box 10)
  - 1946 (Box 10)
  - 1947 (Box 10)
  - 1948 (Box 10)
  - 1949 (Box 10)
  - 1950 (Box 10)
  - 1951 (Box 10)
  - [1952-1954] (Box 10)
    (not received; proceedings for 1953-1955 available in Publications series)
  - 1955 (Box 10)
  - 1956 (Box 10)
  - 1957 (Box 10)
  - 1958 (Box 10)
  - [1959-1961] (Box 10)
    (not received)
  - 1962 (Box 10)
  - 1963 (Box 11)
  - 1964 (Box 11)
  - 1965 (Box 11)
  - 1966 (Box 11)
  - 1967 (Box 11)
  - 1968 (Box 11)
  - 1969 (Box 11)
  - 1970 (Box 11)
  - 1971 (Box 11)
  - 1972 (Box 11)
  - 1973 (Box 11)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 11)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 11)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - 1980/1981-2000/2001, 2 folders (Box 11)
- Reports
  - State Chairmen Reports before 1928
    - A-Z, 3 volumes (Box 12)
  - Chapter Regents Reports 1906-1921
    - A-Z, 3 volumes (Box 13)
  - State Officers Reports 1909-1929 (Box 14)
  - State Conference Chapter Reports
    - 1924-1925 (Box 14)
    - 1925-1926 (Box 14)
    - 1926-1927 (Box 14)
    - 1929-1930 (Box 14)
  - State Reports for Continental Congress
    - 1925-1931, 4 volumes (Box 15)
  - Chapter Reports
    - From Organization to 1917 (Box 16)
    - 1917-1919 (Box 16)
    - 1916-1918 (Box 16)
- DAR State Historian
  - Historical record of the organization of Michigan DAR chapters (Box 16)
  - Lineage records from grandparent to Revolutionary War ancestor, 3 volumes (Box 16)
  - Grave Markers, Revolutionary War Soldiers
    - 1931-1933 undated (Box 46)
    - 1937-1939 (Box 46)
    - 1984-1988 (Box 46)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 46)
    - Card file: some files arranged by chapter with name of ancestor and place of marker (Box 46)
      (card file boxes 1-2)
  - Biographical
    - State Regents (Box 46)
    - Chapter Regents
      - Regent's Biographical Information card file: include Regent's name, genealogical information, offices held, education, etc. (Box 46)
        (in card file box 2)
    - Chapter Regents biographical questionnaires 1930s-1940s, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Chapter Regents biographical questionnaires 1940s-1950s, 5 folders (Box 17)
    - Biographical sketch of Sixth State Regent, Mrs. William H. Wait 1914 (Box 17)
      (include photographic portrait)
    - State DAR historians (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Chapter histories -- Reports to State Historian (Box 17)
    - Questionnaire for Chapter Historians (Box 17)
    - Report of Gifts compiled by State Historian, Mrs. Sidney H. Clarkson 1916-1926 (Box 17)
      (attached is published report covering gifts to 1916)
    - Paper: Pioneers Who Came to Homer (Box 17)
  - Research and topical files of State Historian (Box 18)
  - Research and topical files of State Historian (Box 19)
    (continued)
  - War service questionnaires 1917, 2 volumes (Box 20)
  - Record of Red Cross and knitting work done during World War I 1917-1919 (Box 20)
  - War service records 1917-1920, 2 volumes (Box 20)
  - World War II war service records (Box 21)
- Miscellaneous
  - Notebook containing information about individual chapters (Box 22)
  - State Regent's Book containing membership information from the individual chapters (Box 22)
  - State Regent's Book: lists of state and chapter officers, chapter and membership information, etc. 1890s-1930s (Box 22)
  - Delegates to State Conferences
    - 1901-1907 (Box 22)
    - 1912-1924 (Box 22)
    - 1925-1934 (Box 22)
  - Michigan Continental Congress luncheons record book 1937-1942 (Box 22)
  - Scrapbook: Michigan's contribution to the Historian's General national exhibit at the Continental Congress 1932 (Box 23)
  - DAR Library Accession books
    - 1898-1922 (Box 23)
    - 1918-1976 (Box 23)
    - 1976-1994 (Box 23)
  - Report of the State Regent on the National Congress 1928 (Box 23)
  - Michigan Contributions to Constitution Hall 1925-1928 (Box 23)
  - List of memorial chairs given by members of the various state chapters (Box 23)
  - State Finance Committee minutes 1931-1934 (Box 23)
- Chapter Records
  - Original materials
    - Chippewa Chapter (Iron Mountain)
      - Minute book 1910-1948 (Box 24)
      - Membership cards (Box 24)
      - Chronology of the Upper Peninsula with special reference to Dickinson County (Box 24)
    - Cadillac Chapter
      - Scrapbook 1931-1949 (Box 24)
  - Collected materials
    - Abi Evans (Tecumseh) (Box 25)
    - Abiel Fellows (Three Rivers) (Box 25)
    - Alexander Macomb (Mt. Clemens) (Box 25)
    - Algonquin (St. Joseph) (Box 25)
    - Algonquin Chapter, roll call of Pioneer Ancestors of Michigan: questionnaire includes member name and biographical information about member's pioneer ancestor (Box 25)
    - Aquila Sturges (Dearborn) (Box 25)
    - Amos Sturgis (Box 25)
    - Amos Wheeler (North Branch) (Box 25)
    - Ann Gridley (Hillsdale) (Box 25)
    - Anne Frisby Fitzhugh (Bay City, Mich.) (Box 25)
    - Battle Creek (Battle Creek) (Box 25)
    - Big Rapids (Big Rapids) (Box 25)
    - Capt. Samuel Felt (Dowagiac) (Box 25)
    - Charity Cook (Homer) (Box 25)
    - Charles Meseroll (Union City), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Chippewa (Iron Mountain), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Coldwater (Coldwater) (Box 25)
    - Elizabeth Cass (Grosse Pointe Farms) (Box 25)
    - Elizabeth Schuyler Hamilton (Holland) (Box 25)
    - Ezra Parker (Royal Oak) (Box 25)
    - Fort Pontchartrain (Highland Park), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Fort St. Joseph (Niles), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - General Josiah Harmar (Grosse Pointe Park) (Box 25)
    - General Richardson (Pontiac) (Box 25)
    - Genesee (Flint) (Box 25)
    - Gogebic (Ironwood), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Hannah McIntosh Cady (Allegan), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Hannah Tracey Grant (Albion) (Box 25)
    - Isabella (Mt. Pleasant) (Box 25)
    - Jean Torrence (Ithaca), 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Job Winslow (Traverse City) (Box 25)
    - John Alden (Midland) (Box 26)
    - John Crawford (Oxford and Orion) (Box 26)
    - John Sackett (Redford) (Box 26)
    - Keziah Cooley Goss (Ann Arbor, Mich.) (Box 26)
    - Lansing (Lansing) (Box 26)
    - Le Saut de Sainte Marie (Sault Ste. Marie), 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Lewis Cass (Escanaba), 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Louis Joseph Montcalm (Greenville) (Box 26)
    - Louisa St. Clair (Detroit), 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Lucinda Hinsdale Stone (Kalamazoo) (Box 26)
    - Lucy Wolcott Barnum (Adrian) (Box 26)
    - Ludington (Ludington), 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Major John Biddle (Box 26)
    - Marie Therese Cadillac (Cadillac), 4 folders (Box 26)
    - Marquette (Marquette), 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Martin Van Buren (Paw Paw) (Box 26)
    - Mary Marshall (Marshall) (Box 26)
    - Menominee (Menominee) (Box 26)
    - Muskegon (Muskegon) (Box 26)
    - Nancy DeGraff Toll (Monroe) (Box 26)
    - Nipissing (Lapeer) (Box 26)
    - Ot-si-ke-ta (St. Clair), 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Ottawawa (Port Huron) (Box 27)
    - Pe-to-se-ga (Petoskey), 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Philip Livingston (Howell) (Box 27)
    - Piety Hill (Birmingham) (Box 27)
    - Polly Hosmer (South Haven), 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Rebecca Dewey (Three Oaks) (Box 27)
    - Ruth Sayre (Manistee), 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Saginaw (Saginaw), 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Sarah Ann Cochrane (Plymouth-Northville) (Box 27)
    - Sarah Caswell Angell (Ann Arbor) (Box 27)
    - Sarah Treat Prudden (Jackson) (Box 27)
    - Shiawassee (Owosso) (Box 27)
    - Sophie de Marsac Campau (Grand Rapids) (Box 27)
    - Stevens T. Mason (Ionia) (Box 27)
    - Three Flags (Southfield Township) (Box 27)
    - Ypsilanti (Ypsilanti) (Box 27)
    - Ypsilanti Chapter, roll call of Pioneer Ancestors of Michigan: questionnaire includes member name and biographical information about member's pioneer ancestor (Box 27)
  - Yearbooks
    - Abi Evans Chapter 1927-2000 (Box 28)
    - Abiel Fellows Chapter 1910-2009 (Box 28)
    - Alexander Macomb Chapter 1903-2009 (Box 28)
    - Algonquin Chapter 1911-2009 (Box 28)
    - Amos Sturgis Chapter 1927-2009 (Box 28)
    - Ann Gridley Chapter 1923-1991 (Box 28)
    - Anne Frisby Fitzhugh Chapter 1912-2009 (Box 29)
    - Aquila Sturges Chapter 1929-1932 (Box 29)
    - Battle Creek Chapter 1915-2009 (Box 29)
    - Capt. Samuel Felt Chapter 1924-2009 (Box 29)
    - Charity Cook Chapter 1922-1933 (Box 29)
    - Chief Shawano Chapter 1996-2009 (Box 29)
    - Chippewa Chapter 1914-1945 (Box 29)
    - Coldwater Chapter 1916-2009 (Box 29)
    - Colonel Joshua Howard Chapter 1935-2009 (Box 30)
    - Elijah Grant Chapter 1914-1918 (Box 30)
    - Elizabeth Bienaime Chapter 1985-2009 (Box 30)
    - Elizabeth Cass Chapter 1944-1991 (Box 30)
    - Elizabeth Schuyler Hamilton Chapter 1911-2009 (Box 30)
    - Emily Virginia Mason Chapter 1914-1923 (Box 30)
    - Ezra Parker Chapter 1928-2008 (Box 30)
    - Fort Pontchartrain Chapter 1916-2000 (Box 30)
    - Fort St. Joseph Chapter 1913-1953 (Box 30)
    - General Josiah Harmar Chapter 1941-2009 (Box 30)
    - General Richardson Chapter 1905-2000 (Box 31)
    - Genesee Chapter 1897-1989 (Box 31)
    - Genesee Chapter 1990-2014 (Box 46)
    - Grand Blanc Chapter 1973-1997 (Box 31)
    - Grand River Trail Chapter 1986-2008 (Box 31)
    - Hannah McIntosh Cady 1909-1953 (Box 31)
    - Hannah Tracy Grant 1922-2009 (Box 31)
    - Isabella Chapter 1912-2009 (Box 31)
    - Jean Bessec Chapter 1939-2009 (Box 31)
    - Jean Torrence Chapter 1923-1944 (Box 31)
    - Job Winslow Chapter 1931-2009 (Box 31)
    - John Alden Chapter 1923-2009 (Box 32)
    - John Crawford Chapter 1932-2009 (Box 32)
    - John Sackett Chapter 1942-2009 (Box 32)
    - Keziah Cooley Goss Chapter 1944-1953 (Box 32)
    - Lansing Chapter 1900-2009 (Box 32)
    - Le Saut de Sainte Marie Chapter 1922-1945 (Box 33)
    - Lewis Cass Chapter 1911-1971 (Box 33)
    - Louis Joseph Montcalm Chapter 1924-1952 (Box 33)
    - Louisa St. Clair Chapter 1895-2009, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Lucinda Hinsdale Stone Chapter 1911-2009 (Box 33)
    - Lucy Wolcott Barnum Chapter 1915-2009 (Box 33)
    - Ludington Chapter, no yearbooks (Box 33)
    - Lydia Barnes Potter Chapter 2006-2009 (Box 33)
    - Marie Therese Chapter 1908-2009 (Box 33)
    - Marquette Chapter 1907-1966 (Box 33)
    - Martin Van Buren Chapter 1937-2009 (Box 34)
    - Mary Marshall Chapter 1910-2009 (Box 34)
    - Mecosta Chapter 1964-2009 (Box 34)
    - Menominee Chapter 1916-1973 (Box 34)
    - Michigan Dunes Chapter 1985-2009 (Box 34)
    - Michilimackinac Chapter 1963-2009 (Box 34)
    - Monguagon Chapter 1994-2009 (Box 34)
    - Muskegon Chapter 1910-2009 (Box 34)
    - Nancy DeGraff Toll Chapter 1922-2009 (Box 34)
    - Nipissing Chapter 1967-2009 (Box 34)
    - Onagomingkway Chapter 2006-2009 (Box 34)
    - Ot-Si-Ke-Ta Chapter 1899-1935 (Box 34)
    - Ottawa Chapter 1986-2009 (Box 34)
    - Ottawawa Chapter 1908-1953 (Box 35)
    - Pe-to-se-ga Chapter 1913-1972 (Box 35)
    - Philip Livingston Chapter 1908-2009 (Box 35)
    - Piety Hill Chapter 1935-2009 (Box 35)
    - Polly Hosmer Chapter 1921-1953 (Box 35)
    - Quakertown Chapter 1973-1996 (Box 35)
    - Rebecca Dewey Chapter undated, 1964-2009 (Box 35)
    - River Aux Sables Chapter 1974-2009 (Box 35)
    - River Wabwaysin Chapter 1964-2000 (Box 35)
    - Ruth Sayre Chapter 1912-1932 (Box 35)
    - Saginaw Chapter 1911-2000, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Sarah Ann Cochrane Chapter 1928-2009 (Box 36)
    - Sarah Caswell Angel Chapter 1899-2008 (Box 36)
    - Sarah Treat Prudden Chapter 1913-2009 (Box 36)
    - Sashabaw Plains Chapter 1985-2009 (Box 36)
    - Shiawasee Chapter 1908-1999 (Box 37)
    - Sophie De Marsac Chapter 1907-2009 (Box 37)
    - Stevens Thomson Mason Chapter 1913-1987 (Box 37)
    - Three Flags Chapter 1940-2009 (Box 37)
    - Whispering Pines and Prairie Chapter 2006-2009 (Box 37)
    - Ypsilanti Chapter 1903-2009 (Box 37)
- Publications
  - Bound materials
    (bound set of yearbooks, by-laws, directories, newsletters, state conference proceedings and programs; see also unbound publications for missing years and succeeding years)
    - 1914-1916 (Box 38)
    - 1919-1921 (Box 38)
    - 1927-1930 (Box 38)
    - 1937-1943 (Box 38)
    - 1946-1949 (Box 38)
    - 1949-1952 (Box 38)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 38)
    - State Regency of Mrs. L. E. Holland 1925-1928 (Box 39)
    - State Regency of Mrs. C. F. Bathrick 1928-1931 (Box 39)
  - Unbound publications
    - Bulletins 1937-1941 (Box 39)
    - By-Laws Undated, 1914-1942 (Box 39)
    - Newsletters
      - 1938-1942 (Box 39)
      - 1949-1951 (Box 39)
      - 1961-1965 (Box 39)
      - 1966-1971 (Box 39)
      - 1972-1977 (Box 39)
      - 1978-1984 (Box 39)
      - 1985-1991 (Box 39)
      - 1992-1997 (Box 39)
    - Reports 1915-1976 (Box 39)
    - State Directories
      - 1937-1982 (Box 39)
      - 1982-1999 (Box 39)
    - Yearbooks, State Conference 1917-1926 (Box 39)
    - State Awards Day Programs 1977-2000 (Box 40)
    - State Conference Programs
      - 1904-1970 (Box 40)
      - 1971-1998 (Box 40)
    - Michigan Society Miscellaneous 1940-1965 (Box 40)
    - National Society
      - By-Laws and Immigration Manuals 1924-1932 (Box 40)
      - Continental Congress
        - Proceedings 1944-1991 (Box 40)
        - Programs, Addresses, Reprints from Proceedings 1922-1997 (Box 40)
        - Reports 1929-1991 (Box 40)
      - George Washington Bicentennial Commission 1932 (Box 40)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 40)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook of Mrs. James Brayton 1908-1912 (Box 41)
    (State Regent, 1908-1909)
  - Bicentennial Scrapbooks I and II, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - Michigan Scrapbook 1995-1996 (Volume 7)
    (includes photographs and clippings)
  - Michigan State Pressbook mock-ups
    - 1993 (Volume 8)
    - 1994 (Volume 9)
    - 1995 (Volume 10)
    - 1996 (Volume 11)
    - 1997 (Volume 12)
    - 1998 (Volume 13)
    - 1999 (Volume 14)
    - 2000 (Volume 15)
    - 2001 (Volume 16)
    - 2002 (Volume 17)
    - 2003 (Volume 18)
    - 2004 (Volume 19)
    - 2005 (Volume 22)
    - 2006 (Volume 23)
    - 2007 (Volume 24)
  - State activities
    - 1903-1936 (includes local chapter activities) (Volume 2)
    - 1933-1936 (Volume 3)
    - 1938-1940 (Volume 4)
    - 1943-1946 Michigan Publicity (Volume 5)
    - 1952-1956 (Box 42)
    - 1956-1962 (Box 42)
  - Chapter activities
    - 1910-1934 (Volume 6)
    - 1931-1950 (Box 42)
  - National DAR and Continental Congresses
    - 1893-1931 (Volume 1)
  - Chapter activities 1930-1939 (Volume 20)
  - State historian scrapbook 1996-2006 (Volume 21)
    (include photos, programs, clippings, etc. relating in part to the administration of Jane Moulthrop as state regent)
- Topical files: Activities, Awards, Contests
  - American History Essay Contest 1990 (Box 43)
  - American History Week 1991 (Box 43)
  - Americana 1989 (Box 43)
  - Awards (miscellaneous) (Box 43)
  - Awards 1973-2000 (scattered) (Box 43)
  - Bicentennial Correspondence 1971-1976 (Box 43)
  - Centenary Celebrations 1996 (Box 43)
  - Constitution Week 1995, 1996 (Box 43)
  - Genesee Chapter History 1984 (Box 43)
  - Michigan Juniors 1999 National Junior Membership Doll (Box 43)
  - "Miss Roberta" 1999 National Junior Membership Doll (Box 43)
    (doll fashioned to look like Roberta Stimpson)
  - Outstanding History Teacher Awards 1989-1991, 1995-1997, 6 folders (Box 43)
  - Veterans Memorial Monument, Gibraltar, MI 1988 (Box 43)
  - Historical and Genealogical Record of Michigan DAR, 1988-2000 (Box 43)
    (bound volume)
  - Memorial Service 1997 (Box 43)
  - Tercentenary Celebration 1934 (Box 43)
  - Yorktown Bicentennial 1781-1981, 1981 (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous (unprocessed) (Box 43)
  - Good Citizens Award and related materials (Box 44)
- Photographs
  - Chapters circa 1917-1924
    - Genesee (Flint)-"Doing War Work" (Box 45)
    - Jackson-Dedication of Jackson Memorial May 13, 1924 (Box 45)
    - Lucinda Hinsdale Stone (Kalamazoo)-"Club Room for Soldiers and Sailors" circa 1917 (Box 45)
    - Ludington-Parade, Armistice Day 1923 (Box 45)
    - Menominee-Bay de Noc Trail Dedication August 7, 1919 (Box 45)
    - Sophie de Marsac Campau (Grand Rapids)-"War Relief Society," March 26, 1918 (Box 45)
  - State Board 1952-1973
    - Official photos 1952-1955 (Box 45)
    - State Conference 1973 (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 45)
  - Albums circa 1900-1925
    - DAR, Chapters of Michigan, "War Work"
      - Detroit (photos of Fort Wayne], Ann Arbor, Menominee (DAR Boys Club) (Box 45)
      - Battle Creek, Grand Rapids (Memorial Day parade 1918), Ann Arbor, Mount Clemens (Box 45)
      - Jackson, Detroit, Grand Rapids, Flint, Howell, Petoskey (Registration Day parade 1917) (Box 45)
      - Fort Worth, Texas and Greensburg, Indiana (Box 45)
    - DAR "Michigan" 1920s (Box 45)
      (arranged by chapter; includes photos of various dedicatory ceremonies)
Related Material
The Bentley Historical Library also has records from individual local chapters of the DAR. These chapters include Ann Gridley Chapter (Hillsdale, Mich.), Charity Cook Chapter (Homer, Mich.), Charles Meseroll Chapter (Union City, Mich.), Fort Pontchartrain-Elizabeth Cass Chapter (Grosse Pointe Farms, Mich.), Grand Blanc Chapter, John Biddle Chapter (Trenton, Mich.), Keziah Cooley Goss Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.), Lewis Cass Chapter (Escanaba, Mich.). Menominee Chapter, Quakertown Chapter (Farmington, Mich.), Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.), Shiawassee Chapter (Owosso, Mich.), Stevens Thomson Mason Chapter (Ionia, Mich.), and the Ypsilanti Chapter.